nais.org 2011-12-25

# Legal and Privacy Information

### Legal and Privacy Information

Published: July 22, 2004   
**Updated:** August 5, 2007 

**

Disclaimer

_Please note that the information provided on this website should not be construed as legal advice nor should it be used as a substitute for consulting with legal counsel._

**

**1\. NAIS Privacy Statement**

(a) At the National Association of Independent School (NAIS), we respect and are committed to protecting your privacy. We recognize that our primary responsibility is to meet your interests and needs as a member, affiliate, or friend of NAIS. We also want you to understand how we use your membership information and the choices you can make about the way your information may be collected and used.

**2\. The Information We Collect--Registration**

(a) In order to use certain features of our website, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration, a user is required to give contact information, such as name, e-mail address, school or organization, and job title. This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site in which they may have expressed interest. It will be optional for the user to provide additional information, such as demographic information, and additional personally identifiable information so that we can provide a more personalized experience.

**3\. The Information We Collect and Use--Orders**

(a) Whenever you place an order via this site or register for a conference, information will be requested on an order form. The information requested would include name and shipping address and financial information such as a credit card number and expiration date. This information is used to obtain payment from the appropriate clearinghouse and to fill customers' orders.

**4\. The Information We Collect and Use--Cookies**

(a) Our website does not use "cookie" technology in ways that compromise your privacy. We use a feature of your Web browser called "cookies" to automate certain aspects of our website. Cookies are very small files that are stored on your computer and that enable us to recognize your computer each time you return to our site. By using cookies, we can keep track of your preferences, what you have already seen on our site and what you haven't, and any personalization you've done, without requiring you to enter a password every time you come back.

(b) We do not use cookies in any way that would disclose your personally identifiable information to a third party without your consent. Please be aware that other companies may collect various types of information about you and have different privacy policies and practices. NAIS takes care to ensure its users' privacy, but not every company has comparable policies. Other than NAIS's own site, no site on the Web is under NAIS's exclusive control, not even those sites to which we may provide links. Therefore NAIS cannot assume any responsibility for any other site's content or practices. Providers of Internet sites or services have separate data and privacy practices independent of NAIS that govern the manner in which they use the information that you provide to them. Many websites use cookies to recognize you when you return to their site; some sites require that you provide information before they allow you to enter; some automatically gather information when you visit, such as what operating system your computer runs, what type of Web browser you use, what Internet access provider you use, or what other Web pages you visit; and sites vary greatly (from each other and from NAIS) with regard to how they use such information and to whom they disclose it. We encourage you to exercise care each time you are asked to provide personally identifiable information at a site whose privacy policies you don't know. 

(c) Even at NAIS's site, many of the features and much of the content is supplied by third parties (or jointly by NAIS and one or more third parties), each of which has its own privacy policies and practices. You may be asked to provide personally identifiable information when you register for certain services or promotions on our site; in such cases, the information you provide may be collected and used by a third party rather than, or in addition to, NAIS. Our policy requires such third parties to notify you in advance if they intend to use information you provide for purposes unrelated to the services or promotions for which you sign up, and to give you the opportunity to choose not to use their service rather than share your information with them, but we cannot assume responsibility for their compliance with our policy. 

**5\. More on How We Use Information**

(a) IP Address -- In addition to use of cookies as described above, we use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your preferences and to gather broad demographic information. 

(b) Financial -- We use the financial information you provide about yourself when ordering a product or service, or registering for a conference to complete the transaction. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete the transaction. 

(c) Customization -- We use the information we collect based on usage by those who register with the NAIS Online Services to customize the information on the site to the user's interests.

(d) Identification -- We use the identifying information you provide about yourself for the in-print and online membership directory, and for a variety of organizational purposes, including sharing with you information about NAIS products and services we think might be of interest to you. We offer postal mailing lists for rent to third parties, but we do not sell, rent, or share e-mail addresses with external organizations or individuals.

(e) Surveys -- We use data gathered through surveys and benchmarking studies solely for the purposes described therein. Unless specifically noted otherwise, no personally identifiable information is disclosed in reporting on these surveys and studies.

(f) Demographics -- We use non-identifying and aggregate demographic information to better design our web site and other NAIS services. We also may share such information with associations, organizations and commercial enterprises to help them understand the makeup of the NAIS membership. 

(g) Opting out -- Finally, we do not intend to use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. 

**6\. Public Forums**

(a) The NAIS Online Services makes listserves available to its users. As indicated above, please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personally identifiable information. NAIS listserves and other online services have separate use policies to which users must adhere.

**7\. Supplemental Information**

(a) This site supplements the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties. For example, we may include in your profile data supplied by the institution with which you are employed. 

**8\. Our Commitment to Data Security**

(a) To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

**9\. Links to Other Sites**

(a) This site contains links to other sites. As stated above, NAIS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

**10\. How You Can Contact NAIS**

(a) You can e-mail [info@nais.org](mailto:info@nais.org). 

(b) You can send mail to the following postal address: NAIS, Attention Communication, 1620 L Street, NW, Suite 1100, Washington, DC 20036.

(c) You can call the following telephone number: (202) 973-9700, and ask for the appropriate department.

In conclusion, should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies or other aspects of our user agreement, please send us an e-mail at [info@nais.org](mailto:info@nais.org).

NAIS privacy statement is subject to change. Changes may be made by posting to the website, and are effective upon posting, or upon such other date stated in the posting.
